Guide to the Records of National Conference on Soviet Jewry, undated, 1949, 1954, 1956, 1958-1993 *I-181 and *I-181A
American Jewish Historical Society, Newton Centre, MA and New York, NY
- Part 2, Series XV: Audio Materials on Soviet Jewry and ASJM, 1966, 1968, 1970-1979; Boxes 363-369.
  - Women's Plea, October 30, 1973 (Box 364, Folder 80, 84)
  - An Artist From Vilna, October 30, 1973 (Box 364, Folder 82, 94)
  - Refuseniks, the Human Side, February 12, 1976 (Box 364, Folder 83)
  - Soviet Jewry: A Community Response, November 26, 1973 (Box 364, Folder 85)
  - The Prisoners of Conscience, December 17, 1973 (Box 364, Folder 86)
  - From Kishinev to a Labor Camp, November 18, 1973 (Box 364, Folder 87)
  - 1973 (A Critical Year for Soviet Jews), January 14, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 90)
  - Gulag Archipelago for Jews, January 14, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 91, 122)
  - Chicago an Activist Community, January 28, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 92)
  - Teaching Hebrew Underground, January 28, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 93, 180)
  - Soviet Jews, a Current Situation, March 11, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 98)
  - No Exit for Four Soviet Women, March 25, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 100)
  - Soviet Jewry a Lesson Plan, March 25, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 101, 129)
  - Commentary on the Current Situation on Emigration, April 22, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 103, 119)
  - The Efforts of the Jewish Community of Baltimore and Baltimore Soviet Jewry Committee to Aid Soviet Jews, April 22, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 104)
  - A Report After a Trip to the Soviet Union (Box 365, Folder 105)
  - A News Report: Present Situation of Jews In the USSR, May 23, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 107)
  - Commentary on the Current Situation on Emigration, April 22, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 103, 119)
  - The Efforts of the Jewish Community of Baltimore and Baltimore Soviet Jewry Committee to Aid Soviet Jews, April 22, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 104)
  - A Report After a Trip to the Soviet Union (Box 365, Folder 105)
  - A News Report: Present Situation of Jews In the USSR, May 23, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 107)
  - Prisoners of Conscience a Resource Kit Reading of Excerpts, May 23, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 108, 124, 136)
  - Soviet Jews in Israel, June 5, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 109)
  - An Encounter With Tradition a Report After a Trip to the Soviet Union, June 17, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 110)
  - America Mobilizes, May 20, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 111)
  - Commentary: Travel to the USSR, Part I (Jewish Travel), July 9, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 113)
  - Summit III, the Press Coverage, July 9, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 114)
  - Summit III, the Soviet Jews, July 9, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 115)
  - Travel to the USSR Part II (Jewish Travel), July 9, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 116)
  - August 12 the Night of the Murdered Poets, July 29, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 117)
  - Jewish Identity a Soviet View, July 29, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 118)
  - A Visit to the Soviet Union/Impressions, August 28, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 120)
  - Soviet Foreign Policy, September 4, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 121)
  - Settling in Israel, September 5, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 122, 158)
  - The Days of Awe; Jewish Life in the USSR Vs. Eastern Europe, September 5, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 123)
  - The Inter-Religious Effort on Behalf of Soviet Jews, October 4, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 125)
  - The Student Movement on Behalf of Soviet Jews In Boston, October 15, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 126, 144)
  - Efforts of Canadians on Behalf of Soviet Jews, October 15, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 127)
  - The Jackson Amendment. Where are We Now., October 29, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 128)
  - An Israeli in Moscow for the World University Games in 1973, November 27, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 130)
  - A Women's Plea, November 28, 1974 (Box 365, Folder 133)
  - Prisoners of Conscience, Who are They: Brief Profiles, December 9, 1974 (Box 366, Folder 134)
  - Testing Soviet Law, June 17, 1974 (Box 366, Folder 137)
  - 1974: A Unique Year for Soviet Jews: Jackson Amendment, President Ford's Trade Bill, January 6, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 138)
  - Russia Revisited (Second Visit to the Soviet Union After Four Years), January 14, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 139, 150)
  - A Scientists Campaign, January 14, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 140, 166)
  - Prisoners of Conscience Soviet Jews and the Abuse of the Law, January 27, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 141)
  - Interfaith Concerns, January 27, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 142, 162)
  - Efforts of Canadian Jewry to Help Jews In USSR (Part II), February 11, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 143)
  - The New Jewish Immigrants, February 25, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 145)
  - What is NJCRAC the Meaning of Faith/ Report of the Trip to the Soviet Union, February 3, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 146, 163)
  - The Solidarity Day and the Hardships of Jews in the Soviet Union, March 3, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 147)
  - Alexander and Nina Voronel Interview, April 23, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 149)
  - Australian Jews and the Fight for Russian Jewry, June 4, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 150)
  - The Conference of Leadership Assembly for the Jewish Community, May 8, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 151)
  - A Report From a Recent Trip to Russia, June 4, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 153)
  - Communication With Soviet Jews, June 7, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 154)
  - Moscow Testimony, June 17, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 155)
  - Travel to the Soviet Union: Report, June 7, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 156)
  - The Efforts to Help the Soviet Jews in Los Angeles, June 27, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 157)
  - Reports From a Trip to Soviet Union (Minsk), July 29, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 160)
  - A New Wave of Repression Against Jewish Activists: Declining Immigration, Forced Conscription, August 20, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 164)
  - How do Local Jewish Communities Organize Themselves for Oversees Projects (Israel, USSR), September 20, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 165)
  - Visiting Russia Meeting Jews. a Report From a Trip to the Soviet Union, Part 1, September 22, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 167)
  - How Does a Soviet Jew Become an Activist, September 22, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 168)
  - A Personal History of a Former Soviet Jew First Impressions of Israel's Reality, October 12, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 169)
  - Projecting Ahead the Plans to Aid the Soviet Jewry, October 12, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 170)
  - The Washington Scene, the Concern for the Soviet Jews, October 22, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 171)
  - Connections Between Jewish Activist and Dissident Movement in USSR, October 22, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 172)
  - A Second Trip to Russia (Report) 1975 Trip Vs. 1972 Trip, November 12, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 173)
  - 1976 Conference in Brussels Second International Congress on Soviet Jewry, December 3, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 174)
  - Trade for Freedom, December 3, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 175)
  - A Personal Account, December 23, 1975 (Box 366, Folder 176)
  - Absorption of the Former Soviet Jews in Israel, January 7, 1976 (Box 367, Folder 177)
  - Year Wrap-Up, January 8, 1976 (Box 367, Folder 178)
  - Brussels II: World Conference on Soviet Jewry, January 15, 1976 (Box 367, Folder 179)
  - Interview with Lazar Liubarsky (Box 367, Folder C01)
  - Recorded Statement by Vladimir Slepak, April 26, 1975 (Box 367, Folder C02)
  - Speech by President Gerald Ford on Foreign Policy, 1975 (Box 367, Folder C03)
  - Governor David Hall of Oklahoma Speaking to Emanuel Men's Club on His Trip to Soviet Union, November 7, 1971 (Box 367, Folder C04)
  - Phone Conversation About Refuseniks with Roman Rutman, Moscow, May 11, 1972 (Box 367, Folder C05)
  - Forum -- Soviet Jewry: Developing Community Policies to Meet Changing World Conditions, November 1977 (Box 367, Folder C06)
  - Forum -- Soviet Jewry: Developing Community Policies to Meet Changing World Conditions, November 1978 (Box 367, Folder C07)
  - 45th General Assembly, Bicentennial Perspective: Soviet Jewry, November 1976 (Box 367, Folder C08)
  - Human Rights: Interview With Martin Ennals, Secretary General, Amnesty International, July 11, 1977 (Box 367, Folder C09)
  - Have You Heard: Tom Stoppards Trip to Russia, July 11, 1977 (Box 367, Folder C10)
  - National Leadership Assembly for National Conference on Soviet Jewry, Part 1, August 1975 (Box 367, Folder C11)
  - National Leadership Assembly for National Conference on Soviet Jewry, Part 2, August 1975 (Box 367, Folder C12)
  - National Leadership Assembly for National Conference on Soviet Jewry, Part 3, August 1975 (Box 367, Folder C13)
  - UJA Report: Spring 1972, Zuckerman Campaign Guide (Box 367, Folder C14)
  - Viktor Polsky's Car Accident: Statements of the Victim and Her Doctor, 1974 (Box 367, Folder C15)
  - Victor Fainberg: Bukovsky Press Conference, Interview by Dr. Harry Cargas, August 1976 (Box 367, Folder C16)
  - Briefing of NCSJ Leadership; Speech of Congressman Bill Archer, 1975 (Box 367, Folder C17)
  - Interview with Baruch Goodman, Former Refusenik From Vilna (Box 367, Folder C18)
  - Purim Celebration in Leningrad, 1974 (Box 367, Folder C19)
  - Phone Conversation With Vladimir Slepak and Alexander Luntz, May 9, 1974 (Box 367, Folder C20)
  - Action on Behalf of Soviet Jews During Expo '74 World Fair, Spokane, WA, May 15, 1974 (Box 367, Folder C21)
  - A Phone call to Adina Korenblit, December 10, 1975 (Box 367, Folder C22)
  - Zavorev--Telegram to Rudenko, February 14, 1977 (Box 367, Folder C23)
  - Murdered Poets Demonstration, August 12, 1976 (Box 367, Folder C24)
  - Phone Conversation with Anatoly Sharansky, Dina Relina, February 16, 1977 (Box 367, Folder C25)
  - Conversation with Wife of Alexander Luntz, Moscow, March 11, 1975 (Box 367, Folder C26)
  - Emergency Meeting in Support of Sharansky and Other Soviet Jews Part 1 (Box 368, Folder C27)
  - Unidentified (Box 368, Folder C28)
  - Conference of NCSJ Sponsoring Organizations With 3 House Representatives (Box 368, Folder C29)
  - Phone calls to USSR, April 1, 1972; April 26, 1972 and January 20, 1974 (Box 368, Folder C30)
  - From Moscow: Slepak, Lerner, Luntz, November 26, ? (Box 368, Folder C31)
  - Recording for the Exhibition of Paintings by Boris Penson, Soviet POC, April 1975 (Box 368, Folder C32)
  - Soviet Jews Addressing the Brussels 2nd World Conference on Soviet Jewry, February 1976 (Box 368, Folder C33)
  - Senator Hubert Humphrey Conference, 1976 (Box 368, Folder C34)
  - Tape From W. Lippert, M. Eidelman, Riga, 1973 (Box 368, Folder C35)
  - Lerner, Luntz, Slepak, Goldfarb: Taking in of books, Absorption in Israel (Box 368, Folder C36)
  - Soviet Jews Addressing the Brussels 2nd World Conference on Soviet Jewry, February 1976 (Box 368, Folder C37)
  - World of Soviet Jewry, Program 1: Interview With Jerry Goodman (Box 368, Folder C38)
  - World of Soviet Jewry, Program 3: Discussion--Jerry Goodman, Abe Bair (Box 368, Folder C39)
  - Bnai-Brith, ADL NY, For the Nest, June 28, 1977 (Box 368, Folder C40)
  - Phone Conversation With Valeriy Panov, Russian Language, April 11, 1974 (Box 368, Folder C41)
  - USSR Trip Report Coinciding With Visit of Reps. Green, Yates, Baldwin, Archer, Fenwick (Box 368, Folder C42)
  - Solidarity Day Round Up, Atlanta, Georgia, April 30, 1972 (Box 368, Folder C43)
  - Victor Polsky: Press Conference Upon Arrival to USA, April 9, 1975 (Box 368, Folder C44)
  - NCSJ Leadership Assembly Featuring Alexander Luntz (Box 368, Folder C45)
  - Benjamin Fain: Interrogations by KGB, Needs of Soviet Jewish Community, May 14, 1977 (Box 368, Folder C46)
  - Levich Phone Interview, July 1977 (Box 368, Folder C47)
  - USSR Trip Report and Songs by Two Jewish Musicians (Box 368, Folder C48)
  - Rosh Hashana Service Recorded for Soviet Jews (Box 368, Folder C49)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Moscow II, Parts 3 (Box 368, Folder C50)
  - Phone conversation with Vladimir Zaslavsky, Moscow, August 21, 1972 (Box 368, Folder C51)
  - Alexander Slepak, son of Vladimir Slepak: Statement on Behalf of Soviet Jews, 1977 (Box 368, Folder C52)
  - Volodya Lazaris: Assessment of Sharansky Situation (Box 368, Folder C53)
  - Message by A. Sakharov and Discussion While Recording, November 5, 1977 (Box 368, Folder C54)
  - The Death of Efim Davidovich, 1976 (Box 369, Folder C55)
  - Press Conference on Prisoners of Conscience, March 18, 1975 (Box 369, Folder C56)
  - Alla Smelyanski's Plea, Mark to Commit Suicide, January 1979 (Box 369, Folder C57)
  - Conversations with Moscow and South Bend Indiana, December 10, 1972 (Box 369, Folder C58)
  - Statement on Voice of America by a Soviet Jew (Box 369, Folder C59)
  - Trip Report: Moscow and Lenigrad (Box 369, Folder C60)
  - Phone call to a Soviet Jew on Israel Independence Day, May 7, 1973 (Box 369, Folder C61)
  - Immigration of Soviet Jews: Statistics; Jackson Amendment, 1975 (Box 369, Folder C62)
  - Telephone Conversation With Victor Yochut From Milwaukee, WI, May 1972 (Box 369, Folder M01)
  - Viktor Perlo Commentary, October 16, 1972 (Box 369, Folder M02)
  - American Conference on Soviet Jewry, Israel Communications (Box 369, Folder M03)
  - Soviet Jewry in Israel With Arnold Foster: Interview With Mikhail Zand (Box 369, Folder M06)
  - Soviet Jewry in Israel With Arnold Foster: At the Western Wall With Soviet Immigrants (Box 369, Folder M07)
  - Soviet Jewry in Israel With Arnold Foster: Arrival of Russian Immigrants at Lod Airport (Box 369, Folder M08)
  - Soviet Jewry in Israel With Arnold Foster: Interview with Alla Rusinek (Box 369, Folder M09)
  - Unidentified, December 1, 1966 (Box 369, Folder M10)
  - Topics 44, M. Friedberg (Box 369, Folder M11)
  - Topics 45, M Friedberg (Box 369, Folder M12)
  - August 12, 1952, Murdered Poets Commemoration, 1972 (Box 369, Folder M14)
  - Sam Stevenson, Alan King (Box 369, Folder M15)
  - 50-second Spot Announcement, April 4, ? (Box 369, Folder M16)
  - Press conference, Waldorf-Astoria, Mike Alexandrovich, May 16, 1971 (Box 369, Folder M17)
  - Unidentified (Box 369, Folder M18)
  - NCSJ Plenum, Washington DC, Part 2, June 3, 1974 (Box 369, Folder M19)
  - LA Program on Soviet Jewry (Box 369, Folder M20)
  - Russian: Special Passover Program, for Mr. Buchs--Russian Division, April 28, 1970 (Box 369, Folder M21)
  - Interview with W. N. Lifshitz, November 25, 1970 (Box 369, Folder M22)
  - Cooper Union Demonstration on Behalf of Soviet Jewry, Part 1, December 10, 1966 (Box 369, Folder M23)
  - Cooper Union Demonstration on Behalf of Soviet Jewry, Part 3, December 10, 1966 (Box 369, Folder M24)
  - American Jewish Conference on Soviet Jewry, Sheraton Hotel, April 17, 1966 (Box 369, Folder M25)
  - In contact -- WJR, Anti-Semitism Today, December 11, 1966 (Box 369, Folder M26)
  - January 13th -- Anniversary of Death of S. Mikhoels, December 1, 1968 (Box 369, Folder M27)
  - Ideological Contribution of Eastern European Jewry to the Rise of the State of Israel up to 1897 (Yiddish), May 13, ? (Box 369, Folder M28)
  - Kaminska et al. (Box 369, Folder M29)
  - Prof. Paper and Feffer. (Box 369, Folder M30)
  - Jewish Dimension: Soviet Jewry, March 31, 1970 (Box 369, Folder M31)
  - Unidentified (Box 369, Folder M32)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel: Moscow I, Part 1 (Box 369, Folder M33)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Moscow I, Part 2 (Box 369, Folder M34)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Moscow II, Part 1 (Box 369, Folder M35)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Moscow II, Parts 2 and 3 (Box 369, Folder M36)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Moscow III (Box 369, Folder M37)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Moscow IV (Box 369, Folder M38)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Derbent I (Box 369, Folder M39)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Leningrad I, Part 1 (Box 369, Folder M40)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Leningrad I, Part 2 (Box 369, Folder M41)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Leningrad II, Part 1 (Box 369, Folder M42)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Leningrad II, Part 2 (Box 369, Folder M43)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Vilna I (Box 369, Folder M44)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Vilna II (Box 369, Folder M45)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Georgia (Box 369, Folder M46)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Odessa I (Box 369, Folder M47)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Ukraine (Box 369, Folder M48)
  - Interviews with Former Refuseniks in Israel, Riga (Box 369, Folder M49)
  - Unidentified (Box 369, Folder M50)
  - Call to Russia, April 24, 1972 (Box 369, Folder M51)
- Part 2, Series XVI: Moving Image Film Strips and Videos, undated, 1971, 1987-1988; Box 370.
  The series contain four video tape recordings and one film strip on Soviet Jewry Movement topics.
  - United Jewish Fund-Chicago, News cuts on demonstration-VCR tape, undated (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Greater Miami Jewish Federation, JFTV, Summit Sunday, Washington, DC, VCR tape, December 6, 1987 (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - NCSJ, Yuli Kosharovsky Appeal, VCR tape, March 10, 1988 (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - NCSJ, Kosharovsky, VCR tape, undated (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Israeli Ministry of Absorption, Israel in Color, film strip, 14 min., color, undated (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - "A Time to Rejoice," Russian film, undated (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - UJA, "The Return," film strip, undated (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - NBC. Valery Panov, film strip, undated (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - KCMO-TV, Rita Gluzman interview, Kansas City, MO, film strip, October 14, 1971 (Box 370, Folder 9)